

Contact Me

- +628194160574
- indrawan.semm@gmail.c

Green Hills D5 Jl. Aria

Putra - Ciputat

Tangerang

Selatan,Indonesia



Social Profile

linkedin.com/in/indrawan -mansyah-89544b26

Other Info

Skills

Analytical & Problem-Solving skills, Key Account Management, Communication & Presentation Skills, Selling & Negotiation Skills, Trade Marketing, People Development, Decision Making, Managing

INDRAWAN MANSYAH

Experienced as Country Manager, General Manager Sales, & Head of Sales Capability



About Me

I have more than 15 years experienced in sales (general trade & key account) with complete experience both in marketing and field sales operation as well the sales strategy with solid background in FMCG, consumer electronic & startup company.

I expert in sales, trade marketing, finance and training development with strong negotiation skills, analytic & problem solving, innovative, creative, strong leadership, excellent communication skills and excellence in execution.

Since I worked in a company, I always give them good performance, healty P/L growth, build new business model, new project innovation. I am a team player, self starter, strategic thinker, proactive, innovative and develop my team competency very well.

I haven't miss target when I hold sales divison because I managed the strategy, the execution and increasing my team's capability very well. In my current role, I created new acquisition and retention model, these model resulted double hit sales achievement, decreasing our cost and making positive impact in our P/L.



People, Organization
Development, Leadership,
Effective Time Management,
Change Management, Finance &
Auditing

Awards

2019, Mapan Leadership Development Program & Agent Development Program

2018, New acquisition & retention model for Mapan

2015, SWA - HR Excellence Awards in Training and Development

2010, The Best Selling of Cooking Product in Electronic City

2009 - 2011, Market Leader in Cooking Appliance from 30% to 80% Market Shared (Research from Gfk)

2005 - 2009, The High Flier Employee of PT. Tigaraksa Satria, Tbk.

2004, The Best National of Area Sales Manager PT. Tigaraksa Satria, Tbk.

Languages

Bahasa, English, Deutsch

Experience

Mei, 2018 -Today Mapan - PT. Ruma (Go-Jek Group) | Head Of Sales Capability

Previous Career:

Regional Sales Manager

Lead Training Team to deliver hard & soft skills training for Agent, Front Liner and Manager Level

Build Training Need Analysis (TNA), designing training module, evaluate and analyzing training activity

Managing and monitoring training budget

Ensure knowledge management to be delivered and building a Mapan Culture to be implemented

Jul, 2016 -Today Asia Development Centre & Halifax International Consulting | Senior Trainer & Business Coach (Partnership)

Distribution partnership with Halifax International Consulting in Indonesia to deliver sales capability training

Associated trainer for Asia Development Center to training delivery in sales capability, leadership and strategic management

Business coaching for client

Aug, 2017 -Dec. 2017 Vini International Fze | Senior National Sales & Distribution Manager (GM Sales & Marketing)

Set up and develop the sales goals and business development plan to improve sales and profitability

Set up sales force and KPIs in alignment with company strategy

Manage and improve the relationship with Distributor, Accounts, Outlets and e-Commerce

Interest

Reading, Training Delivery, Traveling, Hiking, Fishing and Rafting

Others

Certified Training Designer and Delivery Professional

Develop effective planning and execution based on volume, revenue, retail program and marketing plan per account and market segment

Manage agreed budgets and evaluate effectiveness of spend, maximize asset utilization and minimize product return

Sep, 2012 -Jun, 2016

PT. Tigaraksa Satria, Tbk. | Head of Training & Organization Development

Lead and manage People Development and Organization Development to be delivered for all employee and ensure knowledge management and culture to be implemented

Training Need Analysis (TNA), training module design and OTIF training delivery, evaluate and analyzing training activity

Build Training Development Program for all employee, including Individual Development Program

Creating talent & qualified employee system for career development

Managing organization chart and performance management system with 360 degree for all division, and designing organizational development, job grading and managing outsourcing partner

Managing and monitoring training budget

Apr, 2011 -Aug, 2012

Rocket Internet GmbH | Country Manager

Develop sales goal and ensure alignment with business strategy, accelerate and deliver business objectives in terms of revenue and margin

Manage sales office and all function in Indonesia to make sure the sales budget is achieved (topline and bottom line)

Monitor, analyze and report on performance – integrate key learning into future plan

Managing and improve the relationship with business partner to expand their business scope, give them information such as market, customer and quality assurance

Manage agreed budgets and evaluate effectiveness of spend

Setup sales team, company policy, key performance indicator and standard of performance for Indonesia Office, and increase employee competency and readiness

Feb, 2009 -Mar, 2011

PT. Indomo Mulia (MODENA) | General Manager Sales

Set up and develop the sales goals and business development plan to improve sales and profitability

Manage sales office, showroom and all sales function in Indonesia to make sure the sales budget is achieved and improve the relationship with traditional dealer, modern dealer, banking and distributor

Accelerate and deliver business objectives in terms of revenue, margin, market share, identify and explore new customers to improve products penetration in Indonesia

Integrated all activities to be draft value proposition for achieve strategy objectives and target business plan, breakdown value proposition to be objectives & target each process, to achieve sales target

Be accountable to the execution of marketing programs in related channels

Business acumen with P&L and A/R control, manage agreed budgets and evaluate effectiveness of spend, maximize asset utilization and minimize product return

Increase employee competency and readiness

Dec, 2003 -Jan, 2009 PT. Tigaraksa Satria, Tbk. | Sales Operation Manager

Previous Career:

- Trade Marketing Manager
- Regional Controlling Manager
- Area Sales Manager

Integrated all activities to be draft value proposition for achieve strategy objectives and target business plan, breakdown value proposition to be objectives & target each process

To communicate draft value proposition with process owner to be final value proposition an continuing innovations value proposition with process owner to fulfill "Needs & requirement customer"

Arrange measurement system performance, made borderless information system for all process, allocate & optimize the resources (A & P) to each channel in order to produce best results

Achieve distribution target according to ideal assortment nationally all of the channels both modern trade & general trade

Analyze market share own and competitors by category product from Nielsen data

May, 1999 -Nov, 2000

PT. International Timber Corporation Indonesia | Cost Audit Supervisor

Audit financial report, especially in cost and expenses, controlling all financial activities, including company budget

Conduct activities related to compliance and confirmation audit, checking all of a suddenly to all division, particularly those related to the company's cost

Insights and make visits to the sites of existing company, and as a facilitator between the company and local resident

ISO14001 auditing of waste disposal company, so that the company remains controlled



Education

2001 - 2003 Brawijaya University - Malang | Magister Management

Magister Management in Strategic Management with GPA 3.50 of 4.00



Projects

May, 2018 - Mapan - PT Ruma (Go-Jek Group) | Soekarno

Project

New model of acquisition & retention (Project Leader)

2016 - 2016 PT. Tigaraksa Satria, Tbk | Hi-5

Building culture with core & enabler compentencies

(Project Leader)

2016 - 2016 PT. Tigaraksa Satria, Tbk | Let's Improve Idea generation & innovation (Adviser)

2015 - 2015 PT. Tigaraksa Satria, Tbk | Hi Coach Everybody is Coach (Project Leader)

2015 - 2015 PT. Tigaraksa Satria, Tbk & PT. Sarihusada | Tiger - TDSC

Training program for sales team (Team Members)

2014 - 2014 PT. Tigaraksa Satria, Tbk | Two is Better

Contextual coaching with tandem selling (Project Leader)

2014 - 2014 PT. Tigaraksa Satria, Tbk | Line Manager as HR Manager

Line manager can do hired and develop his team (Team Members)

2014 - 2014 PT. Tigaraksa Satria, Tbk | e-incentive

	Automation incentive system (Project Leader)
2014 - 2014	PT. Tigaraksa Satria, Tbk Good Warehouse Practices
	Implemented good warehouse practices in our Central Warehouse and Branch Warehouse (Team Members)
2014 - 2014	PT. Tigaraksa Satria, Tbk Drive Your Team How to making easy to achieve sales goal (Project Leader)
2013 - 2013	PT. Tigaraksa Satria, Tbk Safety 1st (HSE) K3, Defensive Driving & Safety Riding (Project Leader)
2013 - 2013	PT. Tigaraksa Satria, Tbk. & PT. Sarihusada Sub Distributor Assessment New assessment for sub distributor with 4 aspects (Team Members)
2013 - 2013	PT. Tigaraksa Satria, Tbk. Sales Force Automation Paperless order system with android (Project Leader)
2009 - 2009	PT. Indomo Mulia (Modena) Sales Analysis System Automation sales analysis for fast decision making
	(Project Leader)

PT. International Timber Corporation Indonesia

1999 - 2000

| ISO 14001

Auditor ISO 14001